

personal website google scholar github.com/daisilin linkedin.com/in/xinlei-lin-in

I am a fourth year Ph.D. candidate in Computational Neuroscience at New York University. I study how sequences of actions in complex environments are made in artificial intelligence and in humans. Currently my research projects focus on comparing deep reinforcement learning algorithms with human planning models, studying the latent factors of complex planning and improving a stochastic log likelihood estimation algorithm.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Ph.D. candidate in Neuroscience (Focus: Planning and Reinforcement Learning)**, *New York University* 2019.9 — present **B.S/M.S in Biochemistry**, *University of California*, *San Diego* 2014.10 — 2019.3

#### **SKILLS**

Tools and Languages Quantitative Research Python, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Matlab, Git, R, JavaScript

Mathematical modeling, Reinforcement learning and planning, Computational cognitive modeling, Neu-

ral networks, Deep learning models, Model fitting methodology, Web development

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Thesis Project 1: Compare planning between AI and humans Wei Ji Ma lab

2021.3 — Present

Center for Neural Science, NYU

- Trained Deep Reinforcement learning models (AlphaZero type agents) to play a planning task of intermediate complexity.
- Analyzed features learned by the trained Deep Reinforcement learning networks.
- Studied the learning and planning mechanisms of AlphaZero agents and compared those to a human planning model.

### Thesis Project 2: Improve the efficiency of an unbiased log-likelihood estimation method

2021.3 — present

Luigi Acerbi lab

Department of Compu

Department of Computer Science, University of Helsinki

- Compared the efficiencies of log-likelihood estimations in different models using Inverse Binomial Sampling with different allocation methods.
- Develop a toolbox for a more efficient Inverse Binomial Sampling method that can estimate the log-likelihood unbiasedly.

# Thesis Project 3: The latent factors of complex planning decisions Wei Ji Ma lab

2020.10 - Present

Coded a battery of 9 planning tasks and cognitive tasks to run a large web-based online study.

• Investigated the individual differences and latent structure of human planning decisions

#### **Rotation project: Hidden Markov Models**

2019.12 — 2020.8

Eero Simoncelli Lab

Center for Neural Science, NYU

Center for Neural Science, NYU, NY

Used Hidden Markov Model to study the context-dependent representations of Visual Cortex.

### Rotation project: deepLabCut for behavior

2019.8 - 2019.12

Christine Constantinople Lab

Center for Neural Science, NYU

• Developed behavioral analysis pipeline by training a convolutional neural network, deepLabCut, to automatically track head angles of rats to infer regret in reward-associated behavior.

#### Large neural population analysis

2017.1 - 2019.6

Takaki Komiyama Lab

UCSD

• Discovered patterns in a large neural imaging dataset to decode neural population activities and to investigate the source of information segregation.

#### **PUBLICATIONS AND CONFERENCES**

X. Lin.\*, Z.Zheng.\*, J.Topping.\*, W.Ma, Comparing Machine and human learning in a planning task of intermediate complexity (Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society, 2022; The Multi-disciplinary Conference on Reinforcement Learning and Decision Making, 2022)

Liu, H., Lin, X., O'Neil, K., DeViso, M., Turner, M., Arroyo, O., Lilascharoen, V., Lim, B.K., and Komiyama, T. Target Cell-Type Specificity of Corticostriatal Activity (2022, paper in preparation)

#### **ACTIVITIES**